<?xml version="1.0"?>
<zine>
<cover id="1">
	<page id="2">
		<body>
		</body>
	</page>
	<page id="1">
	<body></body>	
	</page>
</cover>
<cover id="2">
	<page id="3">
	<body></body>	
	</page>
		<page id="4">
	<body></body>	
	</page>
</cover>
<spread id="1">
	<page id="16">
		<body>Assembled during the Choreographic Coding Labs organized by Motion Bank. Printed during CCL5 at UCLA in September 2015.</body>
	</page>
	<page id="1">
		<body>Atomic, or bite-sized, qualities of movement. 
a <bold>Pocket Reference</bold> for:

* disruptive movement
* computationally-trackable movement</body>
		<footer>V1.0.0</footer>
	</page>
</spread>
<spread id="2">
	<page id="2">
		<heading>Center of Mass</heading>
	</page>
	<page id="3">
	   <heading>Bounding Volume</heading>
		<subheading>Box or Sphere</subheading>
		<body>An area or volume (rectangle, box, circle, sphere) which is as small as possible while still completely containing the performer.</body>
	</page>
</spread>
<spread id="3">
	<page id="4">
		<heading>Reach</heading>
		<body>The action of reaching, with an intended, distant point outside the body, out of reach.</body>
	</page>
	<page id="5">
	   <heading>Level</heading>
		<body>Performer's height from the floor. Example terms: <italic>low</italic>, <italic>medium</italic>, <italic>high</italic>, <italic>lower</italic>, <italic>higher</italic>.</body>
	</page>
</spread>
<spread id="4">
	<page id="6">
		<heading>Circularity &lt;--> Linearity &lt;--> Angularity &lt;--></heading>
	<body>Arrangement of parts of the body in a circular/linear/angular sequence. Also can be movement of parts of the body, or the entire body, along a circular/linear/angular path.</body>
	</page>
	<page id="7">
		<heading>Parallelism</heading>
	</page>
	<body>The amount to which lines extended frm particular body parts (for example the forearms) are parallel to one-another.</body>
</spread>
<spread id="5">
	<page id="8"> 
		<heading>Movement Intensity</heading>
		<body>Amount and speed of movement relative to the performer's position (or Center of Mass). Does not consider gross movement of performer around stage</body>
	</page>
	<page id="9">
	   <heading>Travel Intensity</heading>
		<body>Amount of space recently covered by the performer. Focusing on performer's gross movement around stage</body>
	</page>
</spread>
<spread id="6">
	<page id="10">
	<heading>Isolation</heading>
	<body>moving one or several contiguous body parts while keeping the others still.</body>
	</page>
	<page id="11">
		<heading>Negative Space</heading>
		<body>Created Space, enclosed space, but not inhabited space</body>
	</page>
</spread>
<spread id="7">
	<page id="12">
		<heading>Avoided Space</heading>
		<body>Space which is defined over time by the performer's avoidance of it. Commonly accentuated by angular movement</body>
	</page>
	<page id="13">
		<heading>Gaze</heading>
		<body>Direction or point that performer is looking at</body>
	   <footer>"full-body gaze"</footer>	   
	</page>
</spread>
<spread id="8">
	<page id="14">
		<heading>Points/Areas of Contact</heading>
		<body>points of contact such as where your feet are touching the ground.</body>
	</page>
	<page id="15">
	 <heading>Balance/Sturdiness</heading>
		<body>a function of <italic>Center of Mass</italic> and <italic>Areas of Contact</italic></body>
	</page>
</spread>
</zine>
